Guide to the American Left Ephemera Collection, 1875-2015 AIS.2007.11
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Ethnic Radicalism, VIII.
  - Tie Vapuaten- 10 issues, April 1925- May 1937 (Box 22, Folder 32)
  - "The Real Issue for the Furriers" Greek/English Leaflet, 1940 (Box 22, Folder 33)
  - Cartoons from the Delano Strike- Don Sotaco, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 34)
  - "Israel and Jews in the Soviet Mirror", 1967 (Box 22, Folder 35)
  - "Fight for Democracy and Freedom!" Greek/English Flyer, November 1940 (Box 22, Folder 36)
  - "The Struggle for Peace and Democracy in the U.S.A." American Slav Congress, 1947 (Box 22, Folder 37)
  - Workmen's Circle Tickets, 2, 1955-1956 (Box 22, Folder 38)
  - "40 Years Workmen's Circle: A History in Pictures"- Yiddish/English, 1940 (Box 22, Folder 39)
  - "History of the Workmen's Circle" Maximilion Hurwitz, 1936 (Box 22, Folder 40)
  - "Labor's Enemy: Anti-Semitism", 1945 (Box 22, Folder 41)
  - "...Is it true what they say about Cohen?" Bill Levner, 1948 (Box 22, Folder 42)
  - "Steelyard Blues" NACLA Report, 1979 (Box 22, Folder 43)
  - Unser Vort, Jewish Magazine, January 1950 (Box 22, Folder 44)
  - Der Arbiter Ring- Yiddish Brochure, 1938 (Box 22, Folder 45)
  - Dos Neve Leben- Yiddish Socialist Periodical, 1909 (Box 22, Folder 46)
  - Finnish Socialist and Pro IWW Magazine Annuals: Industrialistin joulu and Punainen Soihtu, 1922-1925 (Box 22, Folder 47)
  - "Towards Fair Play for Jewish Workers" Jewish Congress, October 1938 (Box 22, Folder 48)
  - 20th Year Commemoration of East Los Angeles Riots, January 1991 (Box 22, Folder 49)
  - Jewish Currents: 8 issues, April 1987- December 1988 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Jewish Currents: 10 issues, March 1989- June 1997 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Jewish Currents: 7 issues, May/June 2005- Summer 2010 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Cesar Chavez Poster (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Pamphlet Fraternal Orders Speak for Unionization of the Steel Industry, 1936 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - A Brief History of the American Turnerbund, 1924 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Louise Pettibone Smith, Torch of LIberty (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Tikkun Conference Invitation, 1988 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Jewish Currents; 7 issues, June 1993-November 1994 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Jewish Currents; 7 issues, January 1995-November 1996 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Jewish Currents; 8 issues, April-November 1998 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Jewish Currents; 2 issues, January-February 1999 (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Jewish Currents; 6 issues, November 2003-Autumn 2009 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Jewish Currents; 5 issues, Winter 2009-Spring 2012 (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Jewish Currents; 4 issues, Winter 2013-Spring 2015 (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Jewish Currents; 2 issues, Autumn 2015, Spring 2016 (Box 39, Folder 12)
- Feminism, Gay, Lesbian, IX.
  The sexual and gender politics of leaders of the Old Left generally did not stray very far from conventional bourgeois norms, but their movements nonetheless offered political space for feminists and radical critics of the gender system. The dominant position within both the SPUSA and the CPUSA viewed the "Women Question" as a special case of the Class Question. Capitalism fostered discrimination against women as a way of maintaining a subservient reserve army of labor that could be used to divide workers and lower wages. Only socialism would solve the Women Question. Both parties officially supported equal rights for women and opposed gender discrimination, but top leaders rarely gave these issues priority.
  Nonetheless, both parties offered political space for female activists concerned with gender issues and for thinkers with more penetrating critiques of the gender system than the standard Party orthodoxies. Women with organizational skills, oratorical flair, or literary talents gained visibility and political capital within these Parties as well as access to wider networks of political influence. Both the SPUSA and CPUSA published writings on gender issues that anticipated arguments more generally associated with post 1960s radical feminism.
  Gender issues and critiques of the gender system became much more visible in the New Left than the Old. In part, that reflected the New Left's greater emphasis on personal liberation and quality of life issues. In part, it reflected wider social changes that had started to undermine older gender norms and empowered women (globally as well as in the US)—declining birth rates and increased access to birth control; increased female labor force participation; increased female access to education.
  This greater visibility of political critiques of the gender system also facilitated the emergence of radical movements among Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender sexual minorities. The Old Left rarely addressed questions of sexual identity or the oppression of sexual minorities. Neither the Socialist nor the Communist Party questioned heterosexual orthodoxy, although some anarchists did so occasionally. Some ex-Communists did play notable roles in the early stages of the Gay Rights movement such as several of the founders of the Mattachine Society. But the surge of radical feminism within the New Left encouraged far greater militancy and political visibility among LGBT activists.
  - National News, Birth Control Pamphlet, November, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 88)
  - The Mothers Bill of Rights Pamphlet (Box 5, Folder 89)
  - Feminist Revolution, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 90)
  - The Rhythm Method of Natural Birth Control, By Joseph McCabe, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 91)
  - Sister, New Haven's Women's Liberation Newsletter, February 1, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 92)
  - Woman's Place-In the Fight for a Better World, By Elizabeth Gurley Flynn, March, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 93)
  - Women & The Cuban Revolution, Speeches by Fidel Castro, Articles by Linda Jenness (Box 5, Folder 94)
  - Sisterhood is Powerful, By Betsey Stone, December, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - "Women of New York, WPA Cuts Threaten Your Standard of Living" Flyer (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Women- Vote for Life!, By Ann Rivington (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Women in History, A Recreation of Our Past (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Women and Equality, By Margaret Cowl, February, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Women, War and Fascism, By Dorothy McConnell, December, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Consider the Laundry Workers, By Jane Filley and Therese Mitchell, June, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Women on Guard, How the Women of the World Fight for Peace, By Betty Millard, February, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Women Who Work, By Grace Hutchins, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - What Every Working Woman Wants, By Grace Hutchins, February, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Women in Action, By Sasha Small, February, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Women in the Struggle for Peace and Security, By Claudia Jones, April, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Win Magazine, January, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - The Gay Question, A Marxist Appraisal, By Bob McCubbin, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Mattachine Review (8), November-December, 1955-December, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Front Line of Freedom, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Women and the New World (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Betty Millard, "Woman Against Myth", 1948 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Spectre 3, July-August 1971 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Spectre 4, September-October 1971 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Specter-6, January-February 1972 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Socialist Feminism: A Strategy for the Women's Movement, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Sister: New Haven Women's Liberation Newsletter V.1, N.7, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - The Furies, Lesbian Feminist Monthly, January, 1972- May-June, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Elizabeth Cady Stanton on Socialism (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Women of Yesterday and Today (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Francis Willard on Socialism (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Work Among Women (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Lavender Woman (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Lavender Vision Lavender Vision for the Lesbian Community (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Liberation (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - "The Place of American Women" Pamphlet, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - "The Way We See It" Pamphlet, August 26 1970 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - "Let's Stand Together: The Story of Ella Mae Wiggins", 1979 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - "Women in the War" Elizabeth Gurley Flynn, 1942 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - "The Place of American Women: Economic Exploitation of Women", Joan Jordan, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - "The Working Woman" Periodical, November 1934 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - "A Socialist/Feminist View of the Capitalist Organization of Production" Kathryn Johnson and Peggy Somers, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - "Women" Vol. 6 no. 1, 1978 (Box 23, Folder 9)
- Labor, X.
  The SPUSA and the CPUSA, like virtually all left-wing organizations that considered themselves Marxist, described themselves as parties of the working class although significant portions of their membership were intellectuals, professionals, small business owners and farmers. Indeed, Trotsky, during his brief sojourn in NYC before the Bolshevik Revolution, is alleged to have described the American Socialist Party as a party of dentists and lawyers.
  Since their theory told them that the working class was the agent of historical change, both parties considered participation in the daily workplace struggles of industrial workers as one of their highest political priorities. However, neither party reached consensus on how to relate to the labor movement. Both parties recruited nationally prominent labor organizers and trade union officials (e.g. Eugene Debs, William Z. Foster) as well as significant cohorts of local union officials and labor activists. But the majority of AFL (American Federation of Labor) unions subscribed to Samuel Gompers' strategy of "pure and simple unionism" emphasizing short range limited goals such as wages, hours and working conditions and eschewing advocacy of utopian societal reconstruction such as socialism. Socialists and other radicals critical of the AFL organized the Industrial Workers of the World (IWW) in 1905 as a revolutionary alternative, but many Socialists considered the IWW a sectarian and schismatic division of working class solidarity. Debates over how the Socialist Party should relate to the AFL or the IWW became one of the most important sources of the factional conflict that undermined the SPUSA.
  Similar debates bedeviled the CPUSA. The Party shifted back and forth from a policy of "boring from within" the AFL to a policy of attacking the AFL and sponsoring rival revolutionary unions. Generally these shifts in CP trade union policies corresponded with shifts to the left or right in the Comintern line. In the years immediately after the Bolshevik Revolution, American Communists devoted considerable energy to recruiting the IWW to the Communist movement. As the worldwide revolutionary wave crested without successful revolutions anywhere but the Soviet Union, Soviet leaders sought to consolidate their power and to convince their followers around the world to settle in for a long period of inconclusive political struggle. They urged American Communists to abandon notions of pure revolutionary unions and seek to garner influence within the AFL instead. William Z. Foster, by far the most prominent labor leader in the CPUSA, had organized the Trade Union Education League (TUEL) for labor radicals in the AFL in 1920, and in 1922 the CPUSA and the Comintern adopted and subsidized the TUEL.
  However, during the Third Period (1928-1935) as the Comintern dictated labor policies of pure revolutionary unionism, the CPUSA disbanded the TUEL and organized instead the Trade Union Unity League (TUUL) as a federation of revolutionary Communist unions organized as rivals to AFL unions. With the shift to the Popular Front in 1935, the CPUSA shifted back to engagement with the mainstream labor movement. Fortuitously, this shift corresponded with the appearance of the CIO in 1935. Communists devoted themselves to the CIO and played critical roles in organizing many of the CIO's most important unions. Their dedication to the CIO earned them the regard of many trade unionists who did not necessarily agree with Communist ideology. The political capital Communists earned within the CIO was probably the most important source of the Party's influence in the late 1930s and early 1940s.
  The New Left also had difficulty deciding how to relate to the labor movement. As a middle class movement and as a movement that arose out of disappointment with the Old Left, many early New Leftists doubted Marxist formulations about the historic mission of the working class and tended to view labor union officials as part of the Establishment, e.g. part of the problem more than the solution. On the other hand, as New Leftists moved off campus to engage in civil rights campaigns or community organizing, many began to appreciate both the skills and dedication of veteran labor union activists. This shift in point of view was encouraged by small schismatic Old Left parties such as the Trotskyist Socialist Workers Party (SWP) and the Maoist Progressive Labor Party (PL), both of which had surprisingly large influence within the leading New Left student organization, Students for a Democratic Society (SDS) during SDS's final years. Also, as increasing numbers of student activists graduated from universities they looked for meaningful strategies to continue radical political activity. A variety of New left offshoots, as well as such Old Left parties as the SWP and PL, encouraged them to take jobs in factories, coal mines, and trucking companies. Several thousand former SDS's did so.
  - Textile Strike Bulletin, July 22, 1931 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Automation and Labor, By William Kashtan, October, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Guaranteed Annual Wage, By Wyndham Mortimer, November 20, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - U.S. Labor Looks at Europe, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - The History of the Shorter Workday, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - A Manual of Industrial Unionism, Organizational Structure and Policies, By William Z. Foster, August, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - The Steel Workers and The Fight for Labor's Rights, By William Z. Foster, June, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Organized Labor and the Fascist Danger, By William Z. Foster, August, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Organized Labor Faces the New World, By William Z. Foster, May, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - The Strike Situation and Organized Labor's Wage and Job Strategy, By William Z. Foster, November, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Organizing Methods in the Steel Industry, By William Z. Foster, October, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - The Railroaders' Next Step- Amalgamation, By William Z. Foster (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Halt the Railroad Wage Cut, By William Z. Foster, October, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - What Means a Strike in Steel, By William Z. Foster, February, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Stop Wage-Cuts & Layoffs on the Railroads, A Reply to President T.C. Cashen of the Switchmen's Union of North America, By William Z. Foster, April, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Organize the Unorganized, By William Z. Foster (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - The C.I.O. Convention and National Unity, By Roy Hudson, December, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Labor Unity, What AFL-CIO Merger Means for Workers, By George Morris, March, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Miners Unite!, For One Class Struggle Union, By B. Frank (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Little Brothers of the Big Labor Fakers, By William Z. Foster (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Wrecking the Labor Banks, By William Z. Foster (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - "Do You Know Your Neighbor" (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - The Trade Union Unity League Today, Its Structure, Policy, Program and Growth, By Nathaniel Honig, June, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - The Trade Unions Since the N.R.A., By Nathaniel Honig, April, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Kentucky Miners Fight, By Harry Gannes, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Company Unions, By Robert W. Dunn (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - The White Collar Clarion, January, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - The Trade Union Unity League, Its Program, Structure, Methods and History (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - "Program of The Trade Union Educational League" (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Photograph of a scene at the New Bedford Strike (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Strike Strategy, By William Z. Foster, 1926 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - The Hearst Worker, January, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Gastonia Citadel of the Class Struggle in the New South, By William F. Dunne, 1929 (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Solidarity, June, 1929 (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Industrial Worker, September 30, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Industrial Worker, November 13, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - "General Organization Bulletin", May, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Agricultural Workers Industrial Union Financial Statements (4), 1936 (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Industrial Worker, Official Newspaper of the Industrial Workers of the World, October, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Showdown in Coal: The Struggle for Rank-And-File Unionism, By Linda and Pual Nyden, January, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Issues of Labor Today (2), 1980 (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Workers' Education, A Quarterly Journal, February, 1924 (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Punchin' Out with the Mill Hunk Herald, February 1979 (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - Punchin' Out with the Mill Hunk Herald, May 1979 (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - Punchin' Out with the Mill Hunk Herald, August-September 1979 (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - Punchin' Out with the Mill Hunk Herald, January-March 1980 (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - Punchin' Out with the Mill Hunk Herald, April-June 1980 (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - Punchin' Out with the Mill Hunk Herald, July-September 1980 (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - Punchin' Out with the Mill Hunk Herald, October-December 1980 (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - Punchin' Out with the Mill Hunk Herald, Spring 1981 (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - Punchin' Out with the Mill Hunk Herald, Fall 1981 (Box 6, Folder 74)
  - Punchin' Out with the Mill Hunk Herald, Winter 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 75)
  - Punchin' Out with the Mill Hunk Herald, Spring 1982 (Box 6, Folder 76)
  - Punchin' Out with the Mill Hunk Herald, Fall 1982 (Box 6, Folder 77)
  - Punchin' Out with the Mill Hunk Herald, Spring 1983 (Box 6, Folder 78)
  - Punchin' Out with the Mill Hunk Herald, Winter 1983-1984 (Box 6, Folder 79)
  - Punchin' Out with the Mill Hunk Herald, Fall 1984 (Box 6, Folder 80)
  - Punchin' Out with the Mill Hunk Herald, Spring 1985 (Box 6, Folder 81)
  - Punchin' Out with the Mill Hunk Herald, Winter 1985-1986 (Box 6, Folder 82)
  - Punchin' Out with the Mill Hunk Herald, Fall 1986 (Box 6, Folder 83)
  - Punchin' Out with the Mill Hunk Herald, Summer 1987 (Box 6, Folder 84)
  - Punchin' Out with the Mill Hunk Herald, Summer 1988 (Box 6, Folder 85)
  - "Community Council in Support of Labor Petitions" (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - "Tom Mooney" Files (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - "Smashing Chains, Labor Struggles in Pictures" (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - IWW -- Industrial Worker, November 6, 1920 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Build Labor Party, 1946 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - LC News Letter Vol. 2, No. 3, March 1940 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - LC News Letter Vol. 2, No. 4, April 1940 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - LC News Letter Vol. 2, No. 5, May 1940 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - LC News Letter Vol. 2, No. 12, December 1939 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - LC News Letter Vol. 3, No. 1, January 1940 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - LC News Letter Vol. 3, No. 2, February 1940 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - LC News Letter Vol. 3, No. 6 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - "The Microphone: The Voice of the Worker" Vol. 2 No. 2, May 1935 (Box 23, Folder 29a)
  - "The Microphone: The Voice of the Worker" Vol. 2 No. 3, June 1935 (Box 23, Folder 29b)
  - "The Microphone: The Voice of the Worker" Vol. 2 No. 8, December 1935 (Box 23, Folder 29c)
  - "Industry's Law Against the People" pamphlet, 1948 (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - "The Case for Impeachment of Richard M. Nixon- Now" pamphlet, November 1973 (Box 23, Folder 31)
  - Official Proceedings: First National Convention of United Cannery, Agricultural, Packing and Allied Workers of America, July 1937 (Box 23, Folder 32)
  - "Report on Italy" George Baldanzi, April 1945 (Box 23, Folder 33)
  - "Our Jobs, Our Health, Our Lives, Our Fight" Report, 1980 (Box 23, Folder 34)
  - "Walter Reuther on First Things First" pamphlet, March 1964 (Box 23, Folder 35)
  - "... A burden on the conscience of the American People: The Harry Bridges Case" Philip Murray, 1944 (Box 23, Folder 36)
  - "Here is Your Union!" Henry Kraus, UE Pamphlet, ca. 1952 (Box 23, Folder 37)
  - "Walking Together: Religion and Labor" pamphlet, 1945 (Box 23, Folder 38)
  - "UE Fights for a Better America", 1946 (Box 23, Folder 39)
  - Solidarity Day brochure, September 1981 (Box 23, Folder 40)
  - Haymarket Centennial brochures (2), 1986 (Box 23, Folder 41)
  - "The Sigmon Brothers: Union Busting in Kentucky- Another Case" National Lawyer's Guild, October, 1979 (Box 23, Folder 42)
  - "An Analysis of Our AFL-CIO Role in Latin America or Under Covers with the CIA" Fred Hirsch, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 43)
  - Pitt Professional Union AFT."A Brief History" (2) & Constitution (3), 1980-1982 (Box 23, Folder 44)
  - CIO Year Book, Directory, and Legislative Manual, 1942 (Box 23, Folder 45)
  - "How You Can Tell When They're Planning to Run Away" Mimeo. (Box 23, Folder 46)
  - "The Facts Behind the School Salary Crisis" pamphlet, 1951 (Box 23, Folder 47)
  - "Report on World Unity" pamphlet, 1945 (Box 23, Folder 48)
  - "The Auto Workers Tell the President- Plenty!" pamphlet, 1935 (Box 23, Folder 49)
  - 403s Are Coming Flyer, January 1937 (Box 23, Folder 50)
  - CIO's 1940 Legislative Program for Jobs, Security, and Peace (Box 23, Folder 51)
  - Industrial Unions and Taft-Harley, 1954 (Box 23, Folder 52)
  - "Labor Has Always Led" pamphlet, 1948 (Box 23, Folder 53)
  - "Homes For Workers in Planned Communities through Collective Action", 1943 (Box 23, Folder 54)
  - "We Accuse: The Story of Tom Mooney" Vito Marcantonio, 1938 (Box 23, Folder 55)
  - "Lasting Peace the ILO Way", 1953 (Box 23, Folder 56)
  - "an old foe with a new face" Harry Becker, June 1946 (Box 23, Folder 57)
  - The Dawn of Real Freedom no. 1 "Capitalism on Trial by A Knight of Labor" (Box 23, Folder 58)
  - "The Control of Wages" Walton Hamilton and Stacy May. Workers Education Bookshelf vol. II, 1923 (Box 23, Folder 59)
  - "The Living Constitution" Howard Lee McBain, The Workers Bookshelf vol. VIII, 1927 (Box 23, Folder 60)
  - Pitt Professional Union AFT. Collective Bargaining Items (6), 1980-1982 (Box 23, Folder 61)
  - Pitt Professional Union AFT. "Dear Member" Letters (7), 1980-1982 (Box 23, Folder 62)
  - Pitt Professional Union AFT. Formation Proposal (2) and Member Benefits Statement (2), 1980-1982 (Box 23, Folder 63)
  - Pitt Professional Union AFT. Statement of Positions (2), March, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 64)
  - "Coal Industry Research Guide", National Lawyer's Guild, January 1980 (Box 23, Folder 65)
  - "The CIO and the White Collar Worker" CIO, 1940 (Box 23, Folder 66)
  - "What's Ahead?", CIO Pamphlet, ca. 1947 (Box 23, Folder 67)
  - "Bretton Woods is no mystery" Joseph Gaer CIO pamphlets, ca. 1945 (Box 23, Folder 68)
  - "the answer is Full Employment" CIO pamphlet, ca. 1945 (Box 23, Folder 69)
  - "Vets Can't Eat Medals" UE Pamphlet, October 1946 (Box 23, Folder 70)
  - "The Road to Freedom" Joseph Gaer CIO Pamphlet, ca. 1945 (Box 23, Folder 71)
  - "There's No Place like Home... If you can get one" Joseph Gaer CIO Pamphlet, ca. 1946 (Box 23, Folder 72)
  - "When a Worker Needs a Friend" Joseph Gaer CIO Pamphlet, 1946 (Box 23, Folder 73)
  - "The People's Program for 1946" Joseph Gaer CIO Pamphlet (Box 23, Folder 74)
  - "As We Win" CIO Pamphlet, 1944 (Box 23, Folder 75)
  - "Angels Could Do it Better" Joseph Gaer CIO Pamphlet, 1945 (Box 23, Folder 76)
  - "Labor and Education" CIO Pamphlet, ca. 1946 (Box 23, Folder 77)
  - Analysis of the Taft-Hartley Act, CIO pamphlet, ca. 1947 (Box 23, Folder 78)